Guide to the Chittenden-Lusk Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Chittenden-Lusk family papers
1857-1933
1857-1889
MS 870
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.75
Correspondence among members of the family of Simeon Baldwin Chittenden, his son-in-law, William Thompson Lusk, and correspondence of the Lusk family. Among the Lusk papers are letters and memoirs by Elizabeth Freeman Lusk, mother of William Thompson Lusk, on the deaths of her two daughters in 1864 and 1870 respectively. The family letters also include a series of European travel accounts by Mary H. and William T. Lusk, 1864-1865. Letters by Simeon Baldwin Chittenden to his granddaughter, Anna H. Lusk, in 1885-1889, miscellaneous correspondence among family members and newspaper clippings on William T. Lusk and Simeon B. Chittenden.
Chittenden, S. B. (Simeon Baldwin), 1814-1889
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
Simeon Baldwin Chittenden (1814-1889): merchant in New Haven, 1835-1842; dry-goods merchant in New York City, 1842-; elected to Congress from New York, 1874.William Thompson Lusk (1838-1897): obstetrician; educated in Germany, New York, Scotland, and Austria; member of the New York Infantry Highlanders, 1860-1863; practiced medicine and taught at Long Island College Hospital, 1866-1871; professor of obstetrics and gynecology at Bellevue Hospital Medical College, 1871-1897.
Scope and Contents
Correspondence among members of the family of Simeon Baldwin Chittenden, his son-in-law, William Thompson Lusk, and correspondence of the Lusk family. Among the Lusk papers are letters and memoirs by Elizabeth Freeman Lusk, mother of William Thompson Lusk, on the deaths of her two daughters in 1864 and 1870 respectively. The family letters also include a series of European travel accounts by Mary H. and William T. Lusk, 1864-1865. Letters by Simeon Baldwin Chittenden to his granddaughter, Anna H. Lusk, in 1885-1889, miscellaneous correspondence among family members and newspaper clippings on William T. Lusk and Simeon B. Chittenden.
Death; Families; Europe -- Description and travel; Diaries; Legislators; Merchants; Physicians; Politicians; Chittenden, S. B. (Simeon Baldwin), 1814-1889; Lusk, Elizabeth Freeman; Lusk, Mary Hartwell Chittenden, d. 1871; Lusk, William Thompson, 1838-1897; Chittenden family; Lusk family
- Inventory
  Scope and Contents
  Box 1 processed by Ruth Gay; Box 2 received in 1976 George Vaill addition.
  - Barnard, Horace: letters, 1857-1864 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Chittenden, Simeon Baldwin
    - Correspondence and memorabilia, 1870-1876 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Letters to his granddaughter Anna H. Lusk, 1885-1888 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Letters on his illness and death, 1889 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Newspaper clippings (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Eulogy (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Lusk, Elizabeth Freeman: correspondence and writings on the deaths of her daughters Mary and Lillie, 1864, 1870 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Lusk, Mary: letters, 1860-1861 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Lusk, Mary Hartwell Chittenden: letters, 1861-1871 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Lusk, William Chittenden: correspondence, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Lusk, Willian Thompson: correspondence, 1859-1892 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - ALS from James Clark White, 1833-1916 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Lusk, William T.: newspaper clippings (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Lusk, William T.: newspaper clippings [copies] (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Perkins, Lillie Lusk: correspondence, 1860-1866 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous family correspondence, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Diplomas, certificates, and miscellaneous papers of William T. Lusk, 1859-1878 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Diary of Mrs. Elizabeth Freeman Lusk, 1860 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Travel diaries of William Chittenden Lusk, 1882, 1885 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Travel diary of Anna H. Lusk, 1906 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Diaries of Mary H. Chittenden, 1861-1864 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Travel diaries of (William T. Lusk?), 1893 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Unidentified travel diary, 1861 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Collection of addresses from the memorial meeting for Graham Lusk, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 23)